With an objective function in hand,
拥有目标函数后
we can now think about finding a policy that maximizes it.
现在可以思考如何查找最大化它的策略了
An objective function can be quite complex.
目标函数可能会非常复杂
Think of it as a surface with many peaks and valleys.
可以看做有很多峰值和谷值的表面
Here it's a function of two parameters with the height
图中的函数有两个参数
indicating the policies objective value j theta.
高度表示策略目标值 J(θ)
But the same idea extends to more than two parameters.
但是这一概念可以扩展到多个参数
Now, we don't know anything about this surface.
我们对此表面一点也不了解
So how do we find the spot where the objective value is at its maximum?
如何找到目标值最大的位置？
Our first approach is to search for the best policy by repeatedly nudging it around.
第一个方法是不断到处逼近搜索最佳策略
Let's start with some arbitrary policy pi,
我们从某个随机策略 π 开始
defined by its parameters theta,
该策略由参数 θ 定义
and evaluate it by applying that policy in the environment.
通过将该策略应用到环境中评估该策略
This gives us an objective value,
这样可以获得一个目标值
so you can imagine the policy lying somewhere on the objective function surface.
可以想象策略位于目标函数表面的某个位置
Now we can change the policy parameters
现在 我们可以稍微更改策略参数
slightly so that the objective value also changes.
使目标值也更改
This can be achieved by adding some small Gaussian noise to the parameters.
可以通过向参数添加一些小的高斯噪点来实现
If the new policies value is better than our best value so far,
如果新的策略值比到目前为止的最佳值还要大
we can set this policy to be our new best policy and iterate.
则将此策略设为新的最佳策略并迭代
This general approach is known as hill climbing.
这个一般方法称之为爬山法
You literally walk the objective function surface till you reach the top of a hill.
相当于沿着目标函数表面走动 直到抵达山丘的顶部
Simple, isn't it?
很简单 对吧？
The best part is that you can use any policy function.
最精彩的是你可以使用任何策略函数
It does not need to be differentiable or even continuous,
并不一定要可微甚至连续
but because you're taking random steps,
但是因为采取的是随机步骤
this may not result in the most efficient path up the hill.
可能并不是爬山的最有效路径
One small improvement to this approach is to choose
一个小小的改进是在每次迭代时
a small number of neighboring policies at each iteration and pick the best among them.
选择一小部分周围的策略并从中选择最佳策略
It's easier to understand this by looking at a contour plot.
通过查看等值线图更容易理解
Again, starting with an arbitrary policy,
同样 从随机策略开始
evaluate it to find out where it lies.
评估它并找到它的位置
Generate a few candidate policies by perturbing the parameters
通过随机打乱参数生成几个候选策略
randomly and evaluate each policy by interacting with the environment.
并与环境互动以评估每个策略
This gives us an idea of the neighborhood of the current policy.
这样可以了解当前策略的周围情况
Now, pick the candidate policy that looks most promising and iterate.
现在选择看起来效果最理想的候选策略并迭代
This variation is known as steepest ascent hill climbing and it helps reduce
这种变体形式称之为最陡上升爬山法
the risk of selecting a next policy that may lead to a suboptimal solution.
可以避免选择一个可能会导致次最优解决方案的下个策略
You could still get stuck in local optima.
你可能依然会陷入局部最佳状态
But there are some modifications that can help mitigate that,
但是有一些修改方法可以帮助缓和这种情况
for example, by using random restarts or simulated annealing.
例如 使用随机重新开始法或模拟退火法
Simulated annealing uses a predefined schedule
模拟退火法使用预定义的计划表
to control how the policy space is explored.
控制如何探索策略空间
Starting with a large noise parameter,
从一个很大的噪点参数开始
that is a broad neighborhood to explore,
这时候要探索的临近区域很广泛
we gradually reduce the noise or radius
我们逐渐减小噪点或半径
as we get closer and closer to the optimal solution.
并越来越接近最优解决方案
This is somewhat like a kneeling and iron.
有点像退火和烙铁
By heating it up and then letting it cool down gradually.
通过加热铁块然后逐渐冷却
It allows iron molecules to settle into
使铁分子能够进入最优结构
an optimal arrangement resulting in a hardened metal. Hence the name.
并形成坚硬的金属块 故而得名
We can also make our approach more adaptive to
我们还可以使方法
the changes in policy values being observed.
更加适应于观察的策略值中的变化
Here's the intuition, whenever we find a better policy than before,
原理是 每当我们发现比之前更好的策略时
we're likely getting closer to the optimal policy.
我们就有可能更接近最优策略
So it makes sense to reduce our search radius for generating the next policy.
因此有必要缩小生成下个策略的搜索半径
This translates to reducing or decaying the variance of the Gaussian noise we add.
这就相当于减小或衰减添加的高斯噪点的变化
So far it's just like simulated annealing.
到目前为止 这就相当于模拟退火法
But if we don't find a better policy it's probably a good idea to increase
但是如果我们没有找到更好的策略 则最好增大搜索半径
our search radius and continue exploring from the current best policy.
并继续从当前最佳策略进行探索
This small tweak to stochastic policy search makes it much less likely to get stuck,
对随机性策略搜索进行这一小小的调整使我们不太可能会陷入僵局
especially in domains with a complicated objective function.
尤其是位于目标函数复杂的环境中更是如此